D.M.C.T. Krishantha

charukatharindhu@gmail.com — +94 783901888 — 248/7, Kaduwela Road, Malabe, Sri Lanka linkedin.com/in/charuka-tharindhu-9416711b0 — personal-portfolio-website

Professional Summary

Experienced software engineer with a Bachelor's in Information Technology from SLIIT, recognized for roles as a Software Engineer at Hayleys Advantis Limited and an Associate Software Engineer at Virtusa. I've completed a productive internship at Enuri Information System and I am currently working as a MERN stack Software Engineer at Nova Solution.

Work Experience

Full Stack Developer – MERN NOVA Solution (Pvt) Ltd, Colombo 01. VENDERX POS SYSTEM

June 2024 - Present

- Created a specialized POS system for restaurants, optimizing order management, inventory tracking, table management, payments, and reporting.
- Contributed to the development and maintenance of an admin panel and a user-facing web application optimized for tablets.
- Developed a unified backend server.
- Technologies: Node.js, Express.js, React.js, Redux Toolkit, Tailwind CSS, Material UI, MongoDB, and Amazon Web services(AWS) like Elastic Beanstalk, CodeBuild, CodePipeline, CloudWatch, Route 53, S3 Bucket, Load Balancer.

02. AMAZON, ALIBABA, AND EBAY WEB SCRAPERS FOR PLATFORM-PROFIT

- Developed and maintained web scrapers for Alibaba, Amazon, and eBay to facilitate product research for drop shippers.
- Implemented multithreading and bot detection prevention methods using rotating user-agents and pagination techniques.
- Saved all scraped product details in MongoDB and automated the scrapers to run at midnight using apscheduler.
- Technologies: Python 3.12, BeautifulSoup4, Requests 2.3, Selenium, Flask and Packages (Pymongo, random, apscheduler, threading, ThreadPoolExecutor) and AWS services like Elastic Beanstalk, CodeBuild, CodePipeline, CloudWatch, Route 53, Reverse Proxy(Nginx) S3 Bucket, Load Balancer.

Full Stack Developer - MERN (Freelance) 01. SUPERSCONTO

Dec 2023 - June 2024

- Developed a web application to offer detailed information on discounted products in Milan, Italy.
- Created and maintained both an admin panel and a user-facing web app, powered by a unified backend server.
- Technologies: Node.js, Express.js, React.js, Next.js, Redux Toolkit, Material UI, MongoDB, and AWS S3 for storage, and AWS EC2 for hosting with PM2 server and SSL certification.

02. BLOONSOO

- Developed a platform for booking flights, villas, and day trips, with an admin panel for super and hotel admins, integrating user authentication, Google Maps, and payment systems.
- Technologies: Node.js, Express.js, React.js, Next.js, Redux Toolkit, Material UI, MongoDB, and AWS S3 for storage, and AWS EC2 for hosting with PM2 server and SSL certification.

Software Engineer

Hayleys Advantis Limited, Colombo

01. INLAND CONTAINER DEPO

- Developed and maintained an application for Logistics International Limited, supporting container depot operations at Welisara and Sedawatta.
- Conducted production releases, debugged issues, and provided 24/7 support.
- Technologies: Angular.js, ASP.NET 4.2, NativeScript, WCF services, SQL, and development tools such as Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, MySQL Server Management Studio, and GitHub.

Associate Software Engineer

March 2022 - April 2023

April 2023 - June 2024

Virtusa (Pvt) Ltd, Colombo

01. ENTERPRISE DIGITAL BOT

- Developed and maintained Lisa, Virtusa's internal support bot, streamlining issue resolutions across HR, IT, Finance, and technical domains.
- Contributed as a ServiceNow and backend developer using ASP.NET core, Azure function, Azure DevOps, ServiceNow platform.

Full Stack Developer Intern

July 2021 - March 2022

Enuri Information System (Pvt) Ltd, Colombo

01. TECHJOBZ.CO

- Contributed to TechJobz.co, an innovative research project designed for IT job seekers, focusing on user-friendly job search features similar to LinkedIn, Top Jobs, and Stack Overflow.
- Technologies: React.js, Node.js, Express.js, Next.js, MongoDB, SendGrid API, Meterial UI,JWT, PayHere payment gateway, SendGrid API, Github.
- Live URL: www.pathintech.com

Education

BSc (Hons) in Information Technology

Jun 2018 - Dec 2022

Sri Lanka Institute of Information Technology (SLIIT), Malabe, Sri Lanka

Skills

- Programming Languages: TypeScript, JavaScript, Python, C#, ASP.NET Core
- Technologies: Node.js, React.js, Express.js, Next.js, Redux Toolkit, MongoDB, MySQL, AWS, Azure
- Tools: Git, Agile, Jira, Swagger, Postman, JWT, REST, JSON
- Frameworks: Material UI, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap
- Soft Skills: Problem Solving, Communication, Teamwork, Technical Support

References

Mr.Lalindu Peris

Lead Consultant Technology, Virtusa

Phone: 94 77 5417372

Solution Architect, Hayleys Advantis Limited

Mr. Kumara Hewage Phone: +94 77 2222180

Associate Technical Lead EFutures Private Limited

Mr. Pathum Kalham Phone: +94 71 756 5094